<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on Peter Elliott</title>
    <link>/tags/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on Peter Elliott</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear Regression</title>
      <link>/post/linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>Linear Regression is a foundational topic in Statistics and Machine Learning. Countless books have been written on the topic, ranging from theory to tips for practitioners. In this post I aim to answer a few important questions:
 What is regression? What does it mean for it to be linear? How does it work? What can we learn when using Linear Regression? When should we be skeptical of results?  What is Regression?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Methods from 35,000 Feet</title>
      <link>/post/statistical-methods-from-35-000-feet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/statistical-methods-from-35-000-feet/</guid>
      <description>The goal of this series of posts is to present some common methods in statistics and machine learning in a way that can help build intuition without an overwhelming amount of mathematical detail. My plan is to cover the following topics &amp;ndash; links will appear as posts go up:
 Linear Regression Logistic Regression and Generalized Linear Models Shrinkage and Sparsity Bayesian Inference Bayesian Classifiers Linear Discriminant Analysis, Naive Bayes and Nearest Shrunken Centroids Decision Trees Nearest Neighbors Random Forests and Bagging Support Vector Machines Boosting and Ensemble Methods Kernel Density Estimation and Regression Basis Methods for Nonparametric Regression Principal Components Analysis Matrix Factorization K-Means Clustering Hierarchical Clustering Neural Networks  There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to say about each of these topics &amp;ndash; enough to fill thousands of pages &amp;ndash; so my aim is only to scratch the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>